<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Great Books on Bryan Apperson</title>
    <link>https://bryanapperson.com/series/great-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Books on Bryan Apperson</description>
    <image>
      <title>Great Books on Bryan Apperson</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/series/great-books/</link>
      <url>https://source.unsplash.com/collection/983219/2000x1322</url>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.71.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; Bryan Apperson. Licensed under CC-BY-ND-4.0. Hosted on Github.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 16:09:59 UT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bryanapperson.com/series/great-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Bound</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/prometheus-bound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:57:00 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/prometheus-bound/</guid>
      <description>The scene opens; Prometheus, the fore thinking one, has defied Zeus in giving various knowledge to mankind, thus incurring his wrath. Hephaestus is nailing Prometheus to a craggy mountain face reluctantly, spurred on by Might and Violence. The immediate parallels with the fall of Man present themselves in the modern context. The imagery is inverted, with the rebel suffering at the hands of a tyrannical ruler of the universe for helping mankind.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[The scene opens; Prometheus, the fore thinking one, has defied Zeus in giving various knowledge to mankind, thus incurring his wrath. Hephaestus is nailing Prometheus to a craggy mountain face reluctantly, spurred on by Might and Violence. The immediate parallels with the fall of Man present themselves in the modern context. The imagery is inverted, with the rebel suffering at the hands of a tyrannical ruler of the universe for helping mankind. Prometheus is a fire bringer, one who illuminates. He claims to have liberated man from ignorance. Is man really better off with reason, conciousness and knowledge?
Whether or not man is better off for what Prometheus has done, Prometheus is blessed with the gift of foresight. He knew beforehand the volume of his suffering and how it would come to an end. He still made the choice to ease the suffering of mankind, at his own expense. Prometheus has no fear of death, and has taken the foresight of death away from mankind; thus freeing them to explore knowledge, spurred by the ephemeral nature of mortal existence.
Zeus is presented in the dialectic of the characters as a young tyrant, eager to make an example of those who would defy him. This is what leads to the overzealous punishment of Prometheus, doomed to have his liver eaten daily and never die. This viewpoint of Zeus as arbitrary, capricious and tyrannical is also present in other works of this time period. Aeschylus seems to be solidly on the side of Prometheus in his writing. While Prometheus&amp;rsquo; actions are seen as a sin by Zeus, they are not in the general story. In furtherance of this, we see the suffering of Io, who is the matrilineal ancestor of Heracles. Prometheus tells her how to end her torture at the hands of Zeus, for his own long term benefit.
Can Might exist without Violence? Does Zeus need to act the tyrant to maintain power? Does Might exist without Force behind it in our world today? Was what Prometheus did a Sin? In some ways we are left with more questions then answers, a lot to chew on.
Prometheus Bound is the central play and remainder of a trilogy written by Aeschylus about the being who created mankind. Although the other plays are largely lost to us, we learn that he was bound for thirty thousand years in the surviving fragments of The Firecarrier. We also know that he was later freed by Heracles in Prometheus Unbound. Zeus allows this in exchange for Prometheus revealing the prophecy of Zeus&amp;rsquo; possible downfall in lying with Thetis, whereby a son stronger than the father would be born. The redirection of this threat leads to the birth of Achilles.
Where to Read or Watch Prometheus Bound I read through the University of Chicago Press edition, which I did not find to be a supremely readable edition, it is also available for free on Project Gutenberg. Reading the play and thinking about how you would direct it, or seeing it live is likely the best way to grasp it fully. In lieu of that, here is the best online production of the play I could find:
  ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:53:00 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>The Odyssey is the story of family, love, justice, virtue, and vice. The tale of how they are woven into civilization. On a basic level, it is about a man&amp;rsquo;s journey home. More deeply, it is about the travails of an abandoned family; it&amp;rsquo;s about the unlawfulness of swaggering masculinity; it&amp;rsquo;s about the forbearance of a faithful wife. An epic of many tales about a man of many twists and turns.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Odyssey is the story of family, love, justice, virtue, and vice. The tale of how they are woven into civilization. On a basic level, it is about a man&amp;rsquo;s journey home. More deeply, it is about the travails of an abandoned family; it&amp;rsquo;s about the unlawfulness of swaggering masculinity; it&amp;rsquo;s about the forbearance of a faithful wife. An epic of many tales about a man of many twists and turns.
Odysseus Odysseus, like all, is a flawed man. The man of strife is the inverse of hot Achilles, in his serene, calculated wisdom. He leaves his family to fight a war. Ten years on, with the war won and plunder shared, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly rush home. Depending on which of the two stories the man of convolutions tells is true, he was either sold into slavery or had ten years of supernatural journeys. The former paints him as the better man, though foolish with his endless raiding. The later portrays him as the unfaithful husband, an absentee father, in no hurry to return home. Eventually, with the help of the Phaeacians, a lawful people, he returns home. There he restores the law and regains marital unity.
Penelope Penelope is the anti-Clytaemestra, standing by her family against suitors rather than betraying them; she is everything Helen is not. She is the ideal wife, as seen by Agamemnon in Hades, loyal, long-suffering, wise, holding the walls against the dissolution of hearth and home. She is faithful and sacrifices endlessly to defend Telemachus, spending twenty years of her prime with a missing husband.
Telemachus Telemachus provides the prototypical coming of age story. From a boy, he grows into a lethal force and devises a plan to seize the reins of manhood. He becomes a lawful and righteous man, even without the guidance of his father. This is a contrast to the suitors, who, despite the presence of fathers, grow into swaggering fools.
Antinous Antinous is the opposite of Telemachus in lawfulness, and the inverse of Odysseus&amp;rsquo; high intellect, in low cunning. He is the epitome of the spoiled brat, grown into a violent and entitled man, a man who is to eventually be on the receiving end of a red wedding, old testament justice.
Eumaeus Eumaeus is the exemplar of loyalty and lawfulness in the common man, the antithesis of Melanthius. his honorable nature raises him above the suitors, high in station, who debase themselves by flouting justice.
Takeaways This tale addresses vice and virtue in all walks of life; a juxtaposition of right and wrong. The suitors and Telemachus in nobility, Eumaeus and Melanthius as common men, Odysseus as the beggar and Arnaeus as the poor.
This tale of tales, about the man of twists and turns, highlights the marital bed and unity of the family; it weaves the fabric of civilization from its fibers. It illuminates home as the most important place to be. It is a cautionary tale for those who would tarry away from home in search of wealth and glory, one that tells a story of returning home to find it no longer there. It elucidates true wisdom as fidelity, hospitality, and a swift return to those you love.
Thoughts on the Robert Fagles Translation I read through the Robert Fagles translation and found it enjoyable, more so than his Iliad. The reading was rich in imagery and, although I don&amp;rsquo;t know ancient Greek yet to judge against Homer, it definitely had beautiful poetry. This read almost like a modern novel. There were few or no awkwardly rendered portions. It was something you could sit down and really fall into.
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iliad</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-iliad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:51:00 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-iliad/</guid>
      <description>The Iliad is a brutal war epic, perhaps the war epic. I started reading it back in August 2019. During the reading, I attended two seminars to discuss the book, and completed it in November. It was a hard read for me. That may have been because of the constant, grinding, unreal level of violence portrayed. Though this was my first reading of The Iliad, I will hazard a summary to crystalize my understanding.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Iliad is a brutal war epic, perhaps the war epic. I started reading it back in August 2019. During the reading, I attended two seminars to discuss the book, and completed it in November. It was a hard read for me. That may have been because of the constant, grinding, unreal level of violence portrayed. Though this was my first reading of The Iliad, I will hazard a summary to crystalize my understanding. The Iliad, in my reading, is a book about pride, rage, humility, the nature of men, and the horror of war, at least. The work illustrates amply the folly of rage and pride, as embodied in the characters it portrays.
Pride is a factor in various plots and schemes throughout. For example, Apollo, angered at the pride of Agamemnon, uses that pride against him to sow dissent with Achilles. This causes the death of many. In turn, Achilles own pride causes the death of his best friend, Patroclus. The moral I take from this is that humility, as shown by Priam in this story, can avoid unneeded violence. Hector, as I see it a hero of the story, is killed due to his sense of duty. This, combined with pride, in thinking he can face Achilles alone. Ultimately he dies in vain. Pride and vanity go hand in hand, a recurring theme.
One part of the book, which was brought to my attention in seminar, is the parrallel narratives of the gods and men, with two seperate conflicts taking place. One conflict of the gods, the other of men, who are used as pawns of the gods. The gods, as portrayed by Homer, are as flawed as humans, or moreso. It is the plots, vendettas and favoritism of the gods which are shown to drive the war forward. It is, of course, easier to blame the gods, rather than our own flawed nature.
There are sundry other topics treated in the story, such as the malleability of fate in the eyes of the ancient Greeks. This work, like many of the greats, is something you could come back to again, and again. I think you&amp;rsquo;d keep finding more depth. In fact, since reading, I see echoes of this story in every war movie. The men here are half comic book hero, half real and flawed human.
   Muse, sing the rage of Peleus&amp;#39; son Achilles - Book One, The Iliad    About the Translation The long journey of reading this work started with a short walk, down to a local bookstore. The store, named Logos, seemed a fitting place to purchase my paperback copy of the Robert Fagles translation. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to reread this in the Pope translation. Though I found the Fagles translation enjoyable, I have heard that Pope is worth a read. To that end I might also give the Pope edition a listen on Audible.
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of the Great Books</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/blog/a-study-of-the-great-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 21:21:18 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bryanapperson.com/blog/a-study-of-the-great-books/</guid>
      <description>In August 2019 I became interested in reading the great books of Western Civilization. This interest started whilst considering, at length, the public school system in the United States. Both in consideration of my mixed experiences with it, and in planning for my children’s educations. I have always been an avid reader. However, I haven’t read many of, or studied in great depth, the foundational works of the West. In my research I stumbled upon Online Great Books via the Art of Manliness Podcast.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[In August 2019 I became interested in reading the great books of Western Civilization. This interest started whilst considering, at length, the public school system in the United States. Both in consideration of my mixed experiences with it, and in planning for my children’s educations. I have always been an avid reader. However, I haven’t read many of, or studied in great depth, the foundational works of the West. In my research I stumbled upon Online Great Books via the Art of Manliness Podcast.
This started me on a journey of reading deeply into the western canon as outlined in How to Read a Book by Mortimer Adler. For the time being, I am using Online great books, for a community to discuss these works with. This series contains my musings on the works as I read them and my eventualy contain important resources and study methods.
My Musings on the Great Books
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/an-introduction-to-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 02:20:00 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/an-introduction-to-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>Alfred North Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s An Introduction to Mathematics takes us on a journey of broad strokes, one that traverses the history, notation, and application of mathematical fields. An Introduction to Mathematics is a practical book on theory, great for enticing the study of math at the university level. While covering introductory material, it introduces elegant mathematical insights that will intrigue the reader. It illustrates the principles of generality, form, variable, and abstraction as the elements of mathematics.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Alfred North Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s An Introduction to Mathematics takes us on a journey of broad strokes, one that traverses the history, notation, and application of mathematical fields. An Introduction to Mathematics is a practical book on theory, great for enticing the study of math at the university level. While covering introductory material, it introduces elegant mathematical insights that will intrigue the reader. It illustrates the principles of generality, form, variable, and abstraction as the elements of mathematics.
After touching on the abstract nature of math, we take a look at variables. The work explores essential concepts of any and some. They are the ideas introduced in algebra which allow for concepts like infinity. Applications of variables, such as Boyle&amp;rsquo;s law, are brought to light. Illuminations of how variables work in diverse fields present their usefulness. From Archimedes to Newton, this concept proves itself intrinsic.
From there, we approach vectors and their use in mechanics. All along, talking about the originators of these ideas. The pattern of history, application, and theory continues. The history of mechanics, under the title of dynamics tours from the greeks to Kopernicus and beyond. We learn the concept of vector operations and thereby adding velocities together using the parallelogram law. The explanations are simple yet powerful.
After this digression into applications, the author conveys us back to the realm of pure mathematics. The evolution, and importance, of mathematical notation as a function of abstraction becomes apparent. The discussion of notion naturally leads back to generalizations about real numbers. In contrast to real numbers, complex or imaginary numbers are next. To illustrate complex numbers, we step into the realm of cartesian geometry. An eminent explanation of co-ordinate geometry shows that it serves as a bridge between the quantification of algebra and the pure spacial reasoning of euclidean geometry. As an aside, it seems non-euclidean geometries of curved space were unknown in 1911. Thus, neither were the theories of general and special relativity. Hence some outdated ideas are found, such as molecules in ether.
Traveling on the continuum, we come to conic sections. We explore the properties of various curvilinear shapes. The importance of these shapes is made apparent by touching, once again, upon orbital mechanics. Ironically the Greeks, who originally studied conics, had no application for them. The ancient Greek love of pure theory came to fruition in concrete forms many millennia later; this is a demonstration of essential wonder.
We explore the nature of functions in some depth. The ideas of discrete and continuous functions lead to other concepts. Interval, the approximation to a number within a standard, and the neighborhood of a number approach limits. The book does not visit upon the use of multivariate functions. It also does not touch upon the concept of functions in computing. Although the terminology has changed, the elegance of the elements proves itself in future applicability.
Periodicity in nature, the enormous importance of these periods in how we develop discrete measurements of time, and how they exist in mathematics is the next topic. Mathematical methods used to analyze physical phenomena bring us to the discussion of trigonometry. As discussed in Plato&amp;rsquo;s Timaeus, the whole universe is composed of triangles. We thus take a look at the relationship of these unique rectilinear figures and circles, a special curvilinear conic section, through the lens of the unit circle. The natural occurrence and application of the sine and cosine functions are apparent here.
Earlier on, the treatment of discrete and continuous function approached the idea of limits. Now series are introduced, and limits formally defined in the context of series. Limits and series lead to a discussion on the history and theory of differential calculus. This discussion is complete with a demonstration of how to take the first derivative of a function. Saving the best for last, Euclidean geometry and its nature as the science of dimensional order is next. Lastly, the world of measurement visits the continuum in a discussion of quantity.
At shy of 200 pages, this book covers an immense breadth of ideas. For the most part, it elucidates them readily; I had multiple &amp;ldquo;Aha&amp;rdquo; moments during reading. All considered this was $4, I picked up a used copy on AbeBooks.com (though you can also find it on new on Amazon), and about 20 hours well spent. Rereading this book, after a more in-depth study of the field, would lead to making new connections with what is said. In that line of thought; the bibliography is unique, in that it lays out a plan for self-study through other works. This book may inspire a hunger for mathematical knowledge, read with caution.
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
