<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><title>family on Bryan Apperson</title><link>https://bryanapperson.com/tags/family/</link><description>Recent content in family on Bryan Apperson</description><image><title>family on Bryan Apperson</title><link>https://bryanapperson.com/tags/family/</link><url>https://source.unsplash.com/collection/983219/2000x1322</url></image><ttl>1440</ttl><generator>Hugo 0.81.0</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; Bryan Apperson. Licensed under CC-BY-ND-4.0. Hosted on Github.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 02:52:51 UT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bryanapperson.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agamemnon</title><link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/agamemnon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 21:45:00 UT</pubDate><dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator><guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/agamemnon/</guid><description>As the first play of The Orestia opens, the Trojan war is ending. The watchman, straggling the Atreidae&amp;rsquo;s roof dogwise, sees the beacon signaling victory in Ilium. Agamemnon returns home with Cassandra, a prophetess and daughter of Priam, as a concubine. He has been gone for ten years, with the human sacrifice of his daughter Iphigenia as his farewell. Once home he is greeted by the duplicitous Clytaemestra. She conspires with her lover Aegisthus to kill Agamemnon and seize the reins of power.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[As the first play of The Orestia opens, the Trojan war is ending. The watchman, straggling the Atreidae&amp;rsquo;s roof dogwise, sees the beacon signaling victory in Ilium. Agamemnon returns home with Cassandra, a prophetess and daughter of Priam, as a concubine. He has been gone for ten years, with the human sacrifice of his daughter Iphigenia as his farewell. Once home he is greeted by the duplicitous Clytaemestra. She conspires with her lover Aegisthus to kill Agamemnon and seize the reins of power. The plot thickens knowing, from what the chorus has told the audience, that Agamemnon&amp;rsquo;s father served Aegisthus&#39; father, his brother, his own children for dinner. This play is the quintessential family blood feud.
The Watchman  I speak for those who understand, but if they fail, I have forgotten everything.
Watchman, Agamemnon L36  The Watchman, weary from his long service upon spotting the beacon speaks from atop the house. His location creates the illusion of the house of Atreus, or the nobility, speaking directly to the Chorus. He bemoans the time he has been waiting and subtly hints at the misrule of &amp;ldquo;a lady&amp;rsquo;s male strength of heart&amp;rdquo; and because of it he feels moved to &amp;ldquo;weep again the pity of this house no longer, as once, administered in the grand way&amp;rdquo;. This subtlety indicates his dependence on the rulers. His monologue indicates that he is on the side of the people against the aristocracy, should they have success, in an attempt to straddle the good graces of both sides.
The Chorus  From high good fortune in the blood blossoms the quenchless agony.
Antistrophe C, Agamemnon L755  The Chorus, who represent the people, play a passive role in Agamemnon. The represent the common man. They tell the audience the background story of the House of Atreus and it&amp;rsquo;s curse. They tell of the sacrifice of Iphigenia, Agamemnon&amp;rsquo;s daughter, at the outset of the Trojan war. They hint at a mistrust of Clytaemestra in the beginning. After the murder of Agamemnon they examine Clytaemestra and Aegisthus, the guilt of whom is apparent. They fault Aegisthus for the cowardly act of letting his lover kill his enemy in surprise, rather then facing him directly. Throughout the Chorus acts as an interrogative force and the conscience of the audience. Though the chorus sees the injustices, they are not empowered to act and allow the tyrants to &amp;ldquo;soil justice, while the power is [theirs]&amp;rdquo;.
Clytaemestra  By my child&amp;#39;s Justice driven to fulfillment, by her Wrath and Fury, to whom I sacrificed this man
Clytaemestra, Agamemnon L 1430    Clytaemestra is unfaithful, but can we fault her? Her husband murdered his own child for luck in a meaningless war. His nature and the brutal legacy of his father made it easy to recruit enemies against him. If he had not sacrificed their child in pursuit of a frivolous war, might she have remained true? Was she wrong to plot his demise? What suffering should a person accept from a spouse? Her revenge for her child may have been justified, but lead to the deposition of her son Orestes, long absent, and the utter betrayal of her household. Her primary crime in the eyes of the ancients may have been hinted at in his speech about the &amp;ldquo;lady&amp;rsquo;s male strength of heart&amp;rdquo; in crossing traditional gender role boundaries. She is neither Helen, nor Penelope, but does that make her wrong?
The Herald The Herald announces the return of the pythian, or Apollo blessed, king. This is an appeal so that Apollo may show mercy on the Argives, now that the war has ended. An interchange occurs with the Chorus, where the Chorus Leader makes it apparent that the people have been oppressed under Clytaemestra&amp;rsquo;s rule. The interchange ends with the good news that the war in fact has ended. Clytaemestra&amp;rsquo;s tyranny and lies are seen to possibly be at an end. Unfortunately this hope remains unfulfilled. The herald further recalls the ruin of the Argive fleet, cementing the possibility of a coup.
Agamemnon  In few men is it part of nature to respect a friend&amp;#39;s prosperity withou begruding him, as envy&amp;#39;s wicket poison settling to the heart piles up the pain in one sick with unhappiness, who, staggered under sufferings that are all this own, winces again to the vision of a neighbor&amp;#39;s bliss.
Agamemnon, Agamemnon L 830  Agamemnon returns home victorious, though he suspects that the body politic may have turned gangrenous. The people inform him that, though his crusade was ill recieved, in victory the war for Helen has become palatable. On his arrival he trusts his home to be secure in the hands of Clytaemestra. She twists him into committing pride and idolatry of self by entering the palace walking on a red tapestry, literature&amp;rsquo;s first red carpet. Ironically his role in his namesake play is limited and instead he is more of a backdrop character, killed soon after arrival by his wife.
Cassandra  And drugged to double fury on the wine of men&amp;#39;s blood shed there lurks forever here a drunken rout of ingrown vengeful spirits never to be cast forth.
Cassandra, Agamemnon L 1180  Cassandra, the daughter of Priam, arrives in Argos as Agamemnon&amp;rsquo;s concubine. She is a prophetess, or oracle of Apollo. She prophecies of the death of Agamemnon at the hands of his wife, of her own death, and of the revenge which would befall Clytaemestra. She speaks truly of the vicious cycle of death which is the curse of the House of Atreus. Through her the audience learns of the coming retribution from the one who would kill his own mother. Shortly after revealing this, she dies at the hands of Clytaemestra without a threnoad.
Aegisthus Aegisthus is legitimately grieved; why not seize the opportunity which presents itself? Revenge, a throne, even a queen are up for grabs. He has all the motive and no reason not to indulge it. Once he gains the throne he quickly shows himself to be the tyrant Antinous would have become. While this may be a tragic outcome for Agamemnon, presented by the playwright as the returning hero, I cannot say that Aegisthus&#39; actions were unjustifed. Just or unjust, the perpetuate the cycle of violence which plagues the house of Atreus, and the people suffer for it.
Takeaways The House of Atreus the archtypical family fued. There is more to it than that though. It symbolizes the need for an impartial system of justice and the corruption that inherently occurs in powerful families. The common man sees the injustice here, but is not able to stop it. The cycle of violence continues, draining the land of it&amp;rsquo;s lifeblood. Where will it stop, what levels of depravity will be reached in it&amp;rsquo;s escalation?
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Odyssey</title><link>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-odyssey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:53:00 UT</pubDate><dc:creator>Bryan Apperson</dc:creator><guid>https://bryanapperson.com/musings/the-odyssey/</guid><description>The Odyssey is the story of family, love, justice, virtue, and vice. The tale of how they are woven into civilization. On a basic level, it is about a man&amp;rsquo;s journey home. More deeply, it is about the travails of an abandoned family; it&amp;rsquo;s about the unlawfulness of swaggering masculinity; it&amp;rsquo;s about the forbearance of a faithful wife. An epic of many tales about a man of many twists and turns.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Odyssey is the story of family, love, justice, virtue, and vice. The tale of how they are woven into civilization. On a basic level, it is about a man&amp;rsquo;s journey home. More deeply, it is about the travails of an abandoned family; it&amp;rsquo;s about the unlawfulness of swaggering masculinity; it&amp;rsquo;s about the forbearance of a faithful wife. An epic of many tales about a man of many twists and turns.
Odysseus Odysseus, like all, is a flawed man. The man of strife is the inverse of hot Achilles, in his serene, calculated wisdom. He leaves his family to fight a war. Ten years on, with the war won and plunder shared, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly rush home. Depending on which of the two stories the man of convolutions tells is true, he was either sold into slavery or had ten years of supernatural journeys. The former paints him as the better man, though foolish with his endless raiding. The later portrays him as the unfaithful husband, an absentee father, in no hurry to return home. Eventually, with the help of the Phaeacians, a lawful people, he returns home. There he restores the law and regains marital unity.
Penelope Penelope is the anti-Clytaemestra, standing by her family against suitors rather than betraying them; she is everything Helen is not. She is the ideal wife, as seen by Agamemnon in Hades, loyal, long-suffering, wise, holding the walls against the dissolution of hearth and home. She is faithful and sacrifices endlessly to defend Telemachus, spending twenty years of her prime with a missing husband.
Telemachus Telemachus provides the prototypical coming of age story. From a boy, he grows into a lethal force and devises a plan to seize the reins of manhood. He becomes a lawful and righteous man, even without the guidance of his father. This is a contrast to the suitors, who, despite the presence of fathers, grow into swaggering fools.
Antinous Antinous is the opposite of Telemachus in lawfulness, and the inverse of Odysseus&#39; high intellect, in low cunning. He is the epitome of the spoiled brat, grown into a violent and entitled man, a man who is to eventually be on the receiving end of a red wedding, old testament justice.
Eumaeus Eumaeus is the exemplar of loyalty and lawfulness in the common man, the antithesis of Melanthius. his honorable nature raises him above the suitors, high in station, who debase themselves by flouting justice.
Takeaways This tale addresses vice and virtue in all walks of life; a juxtaposition of right and wrong. The suitors and Telemachus in nobility, Eumaeus and Melanthius as common men, Odysseus as the beggar and Arnaeus as the poor.
This tale of tales, about the man of twists and turns, highlights the marital bed and unity of the family; it weaves the fabric of civilization from its fibers. It illuminates home as the most important place to be. It is a cautionary tale for those who would tarry away from home in search of wealth and glory, one that tells a story of returning home to find it no longer there. It elucidates true wisdom as fidelity, hospitality, and a swift return to those you love.
Thoughts on the Robert Fagles Translation I read through the Robert Fagles translation and found it enjoyable, more so than his Iliad. The reading was rich in imagery and, although I don&amp;rsquo;t know ancient Greek yet to judge against Homer, it definitely had beautiful poetry. This read almost like a modern novel. There were few or no awkwardly rendered portions. It was something you could sit down and really fall into.
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>